<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leonardo Souza</title>
    <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://leogsouza.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Leonardo Souza</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Leonardo Souza</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://leogsouza.github.io/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Leonardo Souza</title>
      <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Learn Data Structures and Algorithms(AGAIN)</title>
      <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/learning-data-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/learning-data-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have over 15 years of experience working as a Software Developer and my biggest frustration it&amp;rsquo;s that I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough knowledge about Data Structures and Algorithms (DSA). So, to fix this, I decided (again) to start from beginning and study DSA improve my knowledge and feel better with myself. To help me to improve my knowledge I will write about every step that I will advance in this journey and share some material I will use to acomplish this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your first program in Go (Golang)</title>
      <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/your-first-program-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/your-first-program-in-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Everyone, when we are learning a new programming language it&amp;rsquo;s common starting with the classic &amp;ldquo;Hello, World&amp;rdquo; program. So this is what we&amp;rsquo;ll do now in Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;ll consider that you have go installed in your machine. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have go installed in your machine please access the &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/doc/install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Go documentation&lt;/a&gt; and follow the steps into installation section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-your-code&#34;&gt;Writing your code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start creating a folder hello in your computer and inside of it create a new file called main.go.
Next, add this content to main.go file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;package main

import &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot;

func main() {
  fmt.Println(&amp;quot;Hello, World&amp;quot;)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look through the code and understand the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first line we have the package declaration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;package main
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every go program is made up of packages and the program start running in package main.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next line we are using a package inside our program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;import &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our case we are using the package &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;fmt&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; to use a function to print a message on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the code we have the function main&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;func main() {
  fmt.Println(&amp;quot;Hello, World&amp;quot;)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Go program has one and only one function main and inside of it you put what your program have to do. In this piece of code we are just calling the function &lt;strong&gt;Println&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;fmt&lt;/strong&gt; package and passing &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; as argument. The function Println from &amp;ldquo;fmt&amp;rdquo; package just print the message passed as argument and appends a new line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executing-the-program&#34;&gt;Executing the program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To execute a go program you have to use the Go command to compile and run the program. 
Inside the folder that you created the main.go, run the command like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;  $ go run main.go
  &amp;quot;Hello, World&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment, that&amp;rsquo;s all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, see you in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World, hello 2020</title>
      <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone, my name is Leonardo Souza and at the beginning of this year I decided to change my old website and create a blog to writing about anything that I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who am I?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a self-taught Brazilian Software Developer that enjoys learning new things and sharing what I learn. I have over 14 years working in a variety of technologies and I am specialized in Backend and API Development a variety of technologies. I also have good experience with Frontend and a little bit with Mobile. When I am not coding, I usually spare my time with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-i-create-this-blog&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did I create this blog?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some reasons encouraged me to create this blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am studying English and I need to improve my skills to become fluent. So, I see that writing is a good way to improve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to boost my coding skills and increase my knowledge in software development. And for me, writing could allow me to understand and explain with more details a specific subject and then master it (applying Feynman Technique).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also want to share my personal experiences that could be useful for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s living a similar situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is my first post and I know that maybe I made some mistakes but I&amp;rsquo;ll improve my writing skills as I write more and certainly give more interesting subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
