<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Leonardo Souza</title>
    <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://leogsouza.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Leonardo Souza</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://leogsouza.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World, hello 2020</title>
      <link>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leogsouza.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone, my name is Leonardo Souza and at the beginning of this year I decided to change my old website and create a blog to writing about anything that I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who am I?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a self-taught Brazilian Software Developer that enjoys learning new things and sharing what I learn. I have over 14 years working in a variety of technologies and I am specialized in Backend and API Development a variety of technologies. I also have good experience with Frontend and a little bit with Mobile. When I am not coding, I usually spare my time with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-i-create-this-blog&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did I create this blog?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some reasons encouraged me to create this blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am studying English and I need to improve my skills to become fluent. So, I see that writing is a good way to improve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to boost my coding skills and increase my knowledge in software development. And for me, writing could allow me to understand and explain with more details a specific subject and then master it (applying Feynman Technique).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also want to share my personal experiences that could be useful for anyone who&#39;s living a similar situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is of my first post and I know that maybe I made some mistakes but I&#39;ll improve my writing skills as I write more and certainly give more interesting subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
